Nick Stein | Software Engineer

nick@nickstein.net (617) 448-1192 Arlington, MA

Profile

Enthusiastic, highly motivated, and empathetic software engineer who is passionate about converting complex concepts into functional code.

Main Technical Skills

• Backend Software Engineering

My passion is developing the systems that the end user rarely interacts with directly, but absolutely must be in place (and function reliably enough) for them to have a satisfactory experience. My preferences lately have been to use Python and run on Kubernetes via Docker images, but if the task requires another language, the core programming tenets are usually the same on other stacks. I have significant experience with JavaScript (Node and client side), C#, and PHP as well, and have dabbled in Ruby, Go, and Java.

DevOps

I have automated countless builds through tools like GitHub Actions, served on on-call rotations, and built custom alarms using tools like Loki, Grafana, OpsGenie, and Nagios. I am very comfortable with Kubernetes and the modern containerized approach to releasing software.

• Linux Administration

Most of my professional career has been spent with Linux as the target environment. These days that means working with Docker images most of the time, but I am comfortable untangling messes on servers. Working with Linux is also a lifelong hobby for me - I have self-hosted applications running on my home network, with automated DNS, HTTPS, and CI/CD.

Project Management

From a project management standpoint, most of my experience has been with the Agile development methodology, using the Atlassian toolset.

Experience

SmarterTravel | Senior Software Engineer | July 2021 - September 2022

- Built and maintained software features for an email pipeline capable of sending over 50 million messages per day on a Python / Kubernetes / Kafka / Redshift stack
- Provided Ops for multiple business units, including maintenance and R&D for shared services, an on-call schedule, developing custom alarms in Nagios and Loki
- Automated a large number of builds for projects on GitHub Actions

Trellis | Software Architect | July 2020 - July 2021

• Built and maintained tooling for automating developer time tracking and client billing

• Assisted engineering teams with spikes and design documentation for novel projects (such as headless e-commerce)

Trellis | Director of Engineering | October 2018 - July 2020

- Facilitated technical escalations from the Tech Leads and Project Management
- Assisted the Project Management team with understanding the unique skills of each developer to help assign the right team members to their projects
- Worked to get IC developers to 80% billable and Tech Leads to 65% billable consistently every week
- Managed the entire backend engineering team, conducting 1x1s, performance reviews and other managerial functions for a team of 15+ full time engineers and contractors

Trellis | Lead Senior Software Engineer | July 2018 - October 2018

- Team Lead for a highly effective software engineering team with several direct reports
- Software Engineering mentor and general Linux/Unix resource for junior developers
- Built several applications to automate internal workflows, integrating tools like Google Sheets and JIRA to generate reports

Trellis | Senior Software Engineer | April 2018 - July 2018

- Architected and built frontend applications using Vue.js that pull data via custom WordPress APIs
- Architected and built integrations with third-party services like point-of-sale and product information management platforms
- Created CI/CD pipelines on various cloud platforms (Bitbucket Pipelines, Codeship, etc.) to automate deployments

Trellis | Software Engineer | September 2017 - April 2018

- Individual Contributor on many Magento 1 and Magento 2 client projects
- Created a highly flexible, admin configurable, SVG-manipulation based frontend application that allows a user to heavily customize a product in Magento 2
- Integrated PACE Anti-Piracy SDK into Magento 2 so that a client's checkout flow could seamlessly deploy licenses to iLok users

GSN Games (Game Show Network) | Software Engineer, Monetization | April 2016 - September 2017

- Built new features for, and maintained existing ones, on an abstraction layer for Unity that controls multiple native video advertising SDKs
- Created a solution for integrating a native survey provider into Unity without leveraging their Android / iOS SDKs
- Created a build script that generated and built an Android Gradle project on Unity 5.3
- Created an Android (Java) plugin to marshall data between a native advertising plugin and Unity

OYO Sports | Junior Software Engineer | July 2014 - March 2016

- Delivered a Magento-based ecommerce solution with a small team under a tight deadline
- Created a distributed graphics automation pipeline leveraging C#, Python, and JavaScript which was used to create multiple product lines consisting of more than 100 SKUs each
- Built a centralized API (Silex) for all of OYO Sports' online infrastructure
- Worked with AWS, Ansible

Education

B.S. Computer Information Technology | Champlain College, 2013

Nick Stein — nick@nickstein.net — (617) 448-1192 — https://www.linkedin.com/in/nlwstein